<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE faq PUBLIC "-//IBM//DTD DITA FAQ//EN" "faq_shell.dtd" []>
<faq id="ditafaq">
  <title>FAQ</title>
  <prolog>
    <author>Eduardo Lago Aguilar, eduardo.lago.aguilar@gmail.com</author>
  </prolog>
  <faqbody>
    <faqlist>
      <faqitem>
        <faqquest>What does BLSS useful?</faqquest>
        <faqans>BLSS automatically installs multiple Linux-Server Systems (called clones) in a short time with almost any effort from the user.</faqans>
      </faqitem>
      <faqitem>
        <faqquest>How does BLSS install small and optimized systems?</faqquest>
        <faqans>By bootstrapping first a Linux-Server Prototype (called proto), getting only the minimal components needed in a server environment, suppressing unnecessary packages, documentation, foreign locale and time zone data, kernel modules, daemons and cache files. The proto is then used to create the target systems (called the clones).</faqans>
      </faqitem>
      <faqitem>
        <faqquest>I had seen many similar scripts, small Linux images, etc. What does BLSS make different?</faqquest>
        <faqans>
          <ol>
            <li>Specialized for Debian and Ubuntu.</li>
            <li>Easy to understand, a small number of nouns and verbs.</li>
            <li>Reduces the installation time of hundreds of Server-systems to just a few minutes.</li>
            <li>A reduced size about 150MB for Debian and 260MB for Ubuntu.</li>
            <li>High usability, with few command line tools, even for non-expert users.</li>
            <li>Reduced number of packages installed, but not in the extreme that could difficult common admin maintenance tasks.</li>
            <li>Small number of daemons on wake up.</li>
            <li>Only essential Kernel modules for a server role.</li>
            <li>A small RAM memory footprint (about 20MB) in a clean install.</li>
            <li>Use of <term>ngetty</term> instead of <term>getty</term>. See ngetty at http://riemann.fmi.uni-sofia.bg/ngetty.</li>
            <li>Locales and time zone data are first class citizens in BLSS.</li>
            <li>Assumes reasonably defaults for all parameters.</li>
            <li>Highly customizable: general, per distro and per suite.</li>
            <li>Support for environments.</li>
            <li>Always uses the latest Linux Kernel version available in the repository or mirror.</li>
            <li>An exhaustive pre optimization at the prototype level after bootstrapping.</li>
          </ol>
        </faqans>
      </faqitem>
      <faqitem>
        <faqquest>Can BLSS-produced systems be shrunk and optimized even more?</faqquest>
        <faqans>Sure, by the user and by the author in the early future. Even without sacrifice an acceptable level of usability.</faqans>
      </faqitem>
      <faqitem>
        <faqquest>Does BLSS perform any Kernel recompilation? </faqquest>
        <faqans>Not necessary until now, It uses the original latest Linux Kernel version.</faqans>
      </faqitem>
      <faqitem>
        <faqquest>What are the requirements for BLSS?</faqquest>
        <faqans>An updated Debian or Ubuntu distribution with plenty hard disk space. </faqans>
      </faqitem>
      <faqitem>
        <faqquest>What about the scale? How BLSS can help me if a need a huge deployment of 1000 server systems for preparing a computational cluster?</faqquest>
        <faqans>It&apos;s where BLSS really shines! In a few minutes with BLSS and enough space you can first create a common server system prototype (called the proto), then use it for create the specific systems (called the clones) with different networking configuration and packages.</faqans>
      </faqitem>
      <faqitem>
        <faqquest>What is exactly a proto?</faqquest>
        <faqans>See <xref href="proto.xml"/> topic.</faqans>
      </faqitem>
      <faqitem>
        <faqquest>What is exactly a clone?</faqquest>
        <faqans>See <xref href="clone.xml"/> topic.</faqans>
      </faqitem>
    </faqlist>
  </faqbody>
</faq>
